RISHI K. MARSENI

LECTURER, AI / ML ENTHUSIAST

+977 9846062807

A Kirtipur - 01, Kathmandu, Nepal

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Energetic and resourceful individual having passion of learning and executing works at highest level of professional ethics. I am a lecturer with over 3 years of experience in the computer science field. I focus on research and presentation on emerging topics related to artificial intelligence, software engineering and information security.

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Computer Vision (Pattern Recognition)

- Human emotion recognition using facial expression classification
- Use of affective computing in the field of psychiatry for mood & behavior recognition of the patients
- Ensuring information security by various cryptographic methods

SKILLS

System:

• Git, Linux, AWS

Programming Languages:

• Php, Python, Java

Database:

• MySQL, PostgreSQL and MongoDB

Design:

• Bootstrap, AngularJS

Frameworks and Libraries:

 Numpy, SciPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Tensorflow/Keras, PyTorch

Documentation:

UML, LaTeX, Zotero

PROFESSIONAL CAREER

LECTURER

Nepal College of Information Technology (June 2019 - Present)

- Principles of Programming Language, Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering, Object Oriented Design and Modeling and Data Structure & Algorithm in undergraduate level
- Involved in training of Deep learning

PART TIME LECTURER

Prime College | National College of Compute Studies (July 2016 - May 2019)

 Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering, Computer Graphics, Advance Database Management System

JR. COMPUTER ENGINEER

Picosoft Pvt. Ltd. | January 2010 - June 2016

- Started a IT company and got an ISP license
- Served internet to my own village
- Designed and developed websites for local businesses

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

POKHARA UNIVERSITY

NEPAL COLLEGE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

MSc. Computer Science | Graduated February 2019

- Graduated with Honors | GPA: 3.92
- Completed a masters thesis on "A novel approach in image cryptography based on Chaos theory and Elliptic Curve "

POKHARA UNIVERSITY

POKHARA ENGINEERING COLLEGE

BE in Computer Engineering | Graduated June 2016

- Completed a final year project named 'ecounternepal.com' which was also awarded by Nepal Telecom Authority
- Worked as an active member in Student Welfare Council